(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T17:40:03.487624",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Dec. 29. 2021
Japan Tokyo
Dec. 29, 2021 / Japan, Tokyo
Watame Tsunomaki
2nd Anniversary
Live Fever!!
Watame Tsunomaki 2nd Anniversary Live Fever!!
「美味しいご飯も、可愛いお洋服も要らない。」
I don't need delicious meals, nor cute clothes.
「歌が欲しい。全部歌にしてお返ししたい。」
I want songs. I want to turn everything into songs and give them back.
「わたしは、」
I...
「歌いたくてホロライブに来たんだよ。」
came to Hololive because I wanted to sing.
足跡を残そう。
Let's leave our footprints.
私が生きた証を。
The proof that I lived.
みんなと一緒に歩いた軌跡を。
The path I walked together with everyone.
「キミだけのメロディ」
祝いの詩
[Kimi dake no Melody] / Poem of Celebration
sweet night, sweet time...
御伽の詩と永久なるミライ
Fairytale Poem and Eternal Future
おはようのうた
Good Morning Song
mayday, mayday
ゼロの足跡
Footprints of Zero
Everlasting Soul
Holidays!
RAINBOW
I walk slowly, but I never walk backward.
mayday, mayday
メーデー 壊れかけてる
Mayday, breaking down,
心がズキッと痛いみたい
my heart aches with a sharp pain.
ベイビー なんて魅力で奇異
Baby, what a charming oddity,
見せるテクニックはすぐに
the technique shown off immediately
クラクラ メーデー それじゃもの足りない
makes me dizzy. Mayday, that's not enough,
すぐにもっともっと呼び出して
call me out even more right away.
Hey! Hey! もっとずらしてよ
Hey! Hey! Shift it even more,
あなたの心に入りたいの ah-
I want to get inside your heart, ah—
見せすいた甘いワナが ah-
That overly transparent sweet trap, ah—
放ってあげようか ah-
Should I let you go, ah—?
自在にコントロールして いたはずなのに
Even though I should have been controlling it freely,
くらくら気味でそう、甘いワナが...
I'm feeling dizzy, yes, that sweet trap...
クラクラ気絶しそうな甘い...
Dizzy enough to faint...
mayday, mayday
mayday 声は届いている？
Mayday, is my voice reaching you?
心はズキッと痛みみたい
My heart aches like a throbbing pain
baby なんて魅力的な
Baby, what a charming
見せるテクニックはすぐにクラクラ
technique to show off, making me dizzy
mayday それじゃ物足りない
Mayday, that's not enough for me
すぐにもっともっと欲張るスタイル
A style that greedily wants more and more
hey hey もっと焦らしてよ
Hey hey, tease me even more
あなたの心に入ってみたいの
I want to get inside your heart
あ 見え透いた甘い罠
Ah, a transparent sweet trap
あ ハマってあげようか
Ah, shall I fall for it?
あ 自在にコントロールしていたはずなのに
Ah, even though I should've controlled it freely
クラクラって酔い出しそうな甘い匂い誘われ
Lured by a sweet scent that makes me dizzy
フラフラって寄ってきちゃうわ
I stagger right over to it
あぁ もう help me...
Ah, someone help me...
逃げたいわけじゃないから
It's not that I want to run away
これくらいがちょうどいいわ
This much is just right
なんてもうキミの前じゃ絶対...
Saying that, in front of you, absolutely...
help meして
Help me!
mayday 舵が取れないの
Mayday, I can't steer the helm
気持ちがモヤっとハレないし
My feelings are hazy and won't clear up
lady なんかじゃいられない
I can't act like a lady
今の時分のgirlはもうチョメもチョメも
A girl of today is doing all sorts of things
絶対あるわけないじゃない
There's no way that's true
絶対にただの勘違い
It's definitely just a misunderstanding
論外 手の平の上で踊らされてる
Out of the question, dancing in the palm of your hand
この感じだってもう溶け出そうような体温に魅わられ
Fascinated by a body temperature that feels like it's melting
なんか 変 あたしじゃないみたい
Something's weird, not like me at all
あぁ もう rescue me...
Ah, someone rescue me...
嫌々って漏れ出しそうなくらいあたしを困らせ
Teasing me to the point of reluctance
なんかもうあたしからは絶対... rescue meして
From me, absolutely... rescue me!
ねえどうして愛は悪戯するんだろう
Hey, why does love play such tricks?
ねえいつかはこの痛みも消えるのか
Hey, will this pain ever disappear someday?
本来は案外簡単に否定して壊れちゃうけど
Originally it's easily denied and breaks apart, but
傷だらけの心は...
this scar-filled heart...
気付けば手を伸ばしちゃってその遠さ苦しくて
Before I knew it, I reached out, and its distance aches
キミも手を伸ばしてくれたら...
If you would reach out your hand too...
イタイ ここにいたいのか
It hurts. Do you want to be here?
cry 落ち着く場所
Cry, a place to settle down
その手で触れてよ ほら mayday
Touch me with those hands, look, mayday
クラクラって酔い出しそうな甘い匂い誘われ
Lured by a sweet scent that makes me dizzy
フラフラって寄ってきちゃうわ
I stagger right over to it
あぁ もう save me...
Ah, someone save me...
help me rescue me save me
mayday
だってもう溶け出そうような体温に魅わられ
Fascinated by a body temperature like it's melting
きっとそう溢れ出しちゃったんだ
It surely overflowed like that
その手でふれてよ ほら mayday
Touch me with those hands, look, mayday
ねえ どうして愛は悪戯するんだろう
Hey, why does love play such tricks?
ねえ いつかはこの痛みも消えるのか
Hey, will this pain ever disappear someday?
その手で触れてよ
Touch me with those hands
クラクラって酔い出しそうな甘い匂い誘われ
Lured by a sweet scent that makes me dizzy
フラフラって寄ってきちゃうわ
I stagger right over to it
あぁ もう mayday...
Ah, another mayday...
クラクラって酔い出しそう
Dizzy enough to get drunk
save me, help me
rescue me, save me
mayday...
だってもう溶け出そうような体温に魅わられ
Fascinated by a body temperature like it's melting
きっと思わず溢れ出しちゃったんだ
It must have accidentally overflowed
キミのままで傷つきそう 溢れ出ちゃったんだ
Staying as you are, getting hurt, it overflowed
もう rescue me...して
Already... rescue me!
rescue me
さあ いつまでも ただ この 地 で 謳おう
Now, let's sing on this land forevermore
胸 を 打ち 震わせる 感動 を 鳴らすように
Resonating emotion that strikes and shakes the chest
いつか もし 灯火 が 消え た って 人 が 生きる なら 謳う 心 は 死な ない
Even if lights ever go out, if humans live, the singing heart won't die
すべて が 壊れ て も …
Even if everything breaks down...
息 絶え た 路上 から 香り だす の は 火薬 と 死 の 匂い such a smell …
From the breathless street, the scent rising is gunpowder and death...
朽ち果て た 荒屋 に 吹きすさぶ 風 哀しみ さえ も ない heart is dead … ？
Wind blowing through the decayed ruins, not even sadness remains...
朝 が 来 たって 降り続く 雨 が 閉ざす 面影 さえ も ない あの 詩
That poem where even traces are closed off by relentless rain when morning comes
今 跡形 も ない この 地 で 謳おう 僅か でも 微か でも まだ 希望 信じ たい から
Now let's sing in this traceless land, wanting to believe in a little hope
奏で 出し 溢れ 出す あの 笑顔 取り戻せる なら 私 の 詩 は 止まらない
If we can take back that overflowing smile, my song won't stop
この 声 が 枯れ た って
Even if this voice grows hoarse
変わり果て て も 変わら ない もの が ある と 目 を 閉じ 浮かべる あの 風景
Closing my eyes, that scenery floats up, knowing things don't change
まだ 共に 鳴らせる 心 が 在る なら 何一つ 無駄 じゃ ない この 詩 も この 愛情 も
If there's a heart we can still ring together, nothing is in vain, neither this song nor love
鬱色 の 伽藍堂 どこまでも 響き渡っ て も 今 は ただ 虚しい だけ
Even if the gloomy empty hall echoes endlessly, right now it's just hollow
でも 願い を 込め て
Still, putting a wish into it
人 の 詩 を 絶やし た もの が 人 の 醜怪 だ と し て も
Even if what extinguished human poetry is human monstrosity
さあ 跡形 も ない この 地 で 謳おう ただ 強く なお強く まだ 希望 信じ て いる から
Now let's sing in this traceless land, still believing in hope, stronger and ever stronger
奏で 出し 溢れ 出す あの 笑顔 取り戻せる なら 私 の 詩 は 止まらない
If we can take back that overflowing smile, my song won't stop
この 声 が 枯れ た って
Even if this voice grows hoarse
滅び た この 街 で
In this ruined town
for the everlasting soul
朝 が 来 たって 降り続く 雨 が 止まざす
Even when morning comes, the relentless rain doesn't stop
おもかげ さえ も ない
There isn't even a trace left
あの 歌声
That singing voice
今 どこ か で も この 地 で 歌 を
Now, somewhere else on this land, let's sing a song
わずか でも かすか でも
Even if it's just a faint, slight amount
まだ 希望 を 信じ たい から
Because I still want to believe in hope
カナデダシ アフレダス アノエガオ
The overflowing, playing smiles...
あの笑顔 取り戻せる なら
If those smiles can be regained
私の歌は 止まらない
My song will never stop
この声が 枯れたって
Even if this voice grows hoarse
for the everlasting soul
変わり果てても 変わらないものが有ると
Even if everything changes, knowing there are things that remain unchanged,
目を閉じ 浮かぶ ああ果てなく
I close my eyes and picture them, oh, endlessly.
ああ果てなく
Oh, endlessly...
まだ共に 鳴らせる 心 が あるなら
If there is still a heart that can resound together,
何一つ 無駄じゃない この歌も この愛も
not a single thing is in vain, neither this song nor this love.
琥珀色の伽藍 どこまでも 響き渡っても 今はただ 虚しいだけ
Even if the amber sanctuary echoes endlessly, right now it is just empty.
でも願いを込めて
But putting my wish into it...
人の歌を 絶やしたものが 人の醜態だとしても
Even if silencing human song is considered humanity's disgrace,
人の歌を 絶やしたものが 人の収穫 耕してさ
what extinguished human song was humanity's harvest—cultivating it—
正しいでも...
even if it's right...
さあ 跡形もない この地で 謳おう
Now, let's sing in this place with no trace left,
ただ強く なお強く まだ希望を 信じてるから
still strongly, ever more strongly, believing in hope.
奏で出し 溢れ出す あの笑顔 取り戻せるなら
If those overflowing, playing smiles can be reclaimed,
私の詩は 止まない この声が 枯れたって
my song will never stop, even if this voice grows hoarse.
変わり果てても 変わらないものが有ると... 滅びたこの街で
Even in this ruined city where things remain unchanged...
for the everlasting soul
みんなー！
Everyone!
こんばん、どどどー！ ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためです！
Good evening, dododoo! I'm Tsunomaki Watame, Hololive 4th Gen!
いや、みんな聞いてくれてありがとうございます！
Man, thank you all so much for listening!
え、今回ね、歌わせていただいた「MeMeMe」と「Everlasting Soul」は
Um, this time I sang "MeMeMe" and "Everlasting Soul"
この衣装で歌ったことがなかったので、選曲させてもらったんですけど、どうだったかな？
in this outfit for the first time, so I chose them, but how was it?
どうだった、どうだった？ よかった？ かっこよかった？
How was it, how was it? Was it good? Was it cool?
頑張ったで！ ありがとう。こうして2周年を迎えられるのも、
I did my best! Thank you. Being able to celebrate our 2nd anniversary like this
本当に応援してくれてるみんなのおかげだと思っています。本当にありがとうございます！
is truly thanks to everyone supporting me. Thank you so much!
ほんな、見る？わためのこの衣装。見る、見たことない人もいると思うんだけど、
So, wanna see? Watame's outfit here. I think there are some people who haven't seen it yet,
見る、見る、見る、見る、見る？見る、見る？ おお、リボンがついてたり、お、
look, look, look, look? Oh, there's a ribbon attached, oh,
腰には、羊わため糸がついてたり、お、
around the waist, there's sheep Watame thread attached, oh,
あ、へそも、あ、シースルーでへそが、へそが... そして、
ah, the belly button too, ah, see-through and the belly button... And,
え、バインバインのお胸だったり、ははは！
uh, bouncy breasts and all, hahaha!
髪型もね、ちょっと違うんだけど、
my hairstyle is also a bit different,
あとはね、爪とかも、お、お、
and also my nails too, oh, oh,
赤いのが塗ってあったり、こっちは手袋なんだけど、塗ってあったり、します！
have red paint on them, or gloves on this side, they're painted, yeah!
あ、あとね、今日のハッシュタグがありまして、
Oh, also, today's hashtag is,
こっちかな？ てんてーん！ 角巻わため2周年ライブで是非たくさんツイートしていただけたら嬉しいです！
over here? Ta-da! I'd be so happy if you could tweet a lot with #TsunomakiWatame2ndLive!
いっぱいスクショとかね、撮ってください。よろしくお願いします！
Please take lots of screenshots and stuff. Thank you so much!
え、そして、この次にお披露目させていただく曲なんだけどさ、
Um, and, the song I'm going to showcase next,
まだ、まだみんなの前で見せたことがない、振り付けだったり、
has choreography that we haven't shown everyone yet,
お、てことは、え、ダンスを踊ったり、するのて、
oh, meaning, um, dancing and stuff, so,
え、ぜひね、楽しんでいただけたらなと思います。
um, I really hope you enjoy it.
一緒に踊ったり歌ったり、サイリウム振ったり、歌ったり、歌ったり歌ったり楽しんでてください！
Please enjoy dancing together, singing, waving penlights, singing, singing!
では、次の曲聞いてください、レインボー！
Now, please listen to the next song, Rainbow!
ねえ 「おはよう」のあと
Hey, right after saying "Good morning,"
もう落ち込んでるの
I'm already feeling down.
やりたいことも怖いからやめにしたい
Things I want to do are scary, so I want to quit.
もうちょっとだけの自分
Just a little bit more of myself...
「もう一歩が踏み出せない」
"I can't take another step forward."
そう言えばオッケーだった逃げていられた
Saying that was fine, I could just run away.
でもきみが笑って「それでもいい」と言うんだったら
But if you smile and say "that's alright too,"
恥ずかしいところとか
My embarrassing moments
ダメダメなところとか見せたくなくなっちゃうでしょ
and my hopeless sides—I wouldn't want to show you, right?
どんな時も前を向いて歌っていたい
I want to keep facing forward and singing no matter what,
ほらへこんで泣いて辛い時も
Look, even when I'm depressed, crying, and hurting,
強がってるけど平気だよきっときみのためのならできること
I'm acting tough, but I'm fine; for your sake, I can do it.
涙を“大嫌い”にばらまいて
Scattering my tears away as something I "hate,"
弱くたって虹は呼び出せるよ
Even if I'm weak, I can summon a rainbow.
また明日もたぶん僕次第で
Tomorrow too, probably depending on me,
今日よりも輝いていく
I will shine even brighter than today.
ねえ 「おはよう」のあと なんか気分がいい
Hey, right after saying "Good morning," I feel pretty good.
もう繰り返しとかない そう思えるよ
I can think to myself, "No more repeating cycles."
意外と怖くないね あくまで個人の感想です
It's surprisingly not scary; that's just my personal opinion.
秘められた力とか 見たことない奇跡とか
Hidden powers or miracles I've never seen before—
そんなの妄想しちゃうかも
I might end up daydreaming about stuff like that.
よーいどんで僕は変わる 合図は君に出してほしい
I will change on the count of three; I want you to give me the cue.
大冒険する準備ならちゃんと君の分までしといたよ
If it's about preparing for a grand adventure, I've got your share ready too.
どんな時も前を向いて歌っていたい ほらへこんで泣いて辛い時も
I want to keep facing forward and singing no matter what, even when I'm crying.
強がってるけど平気だよ きっときみのためのならできること
I'm acting tough, but I'm fine; surely for your sake, I can do it.
涙を“大嫌い”にばらまいて 弱くたって虹は呼び出せるよ
Scattering my tears away as something I "hate," I can summon a rainbow.
また明日もたぶん僕次第で 今日よりも輝いていく
Tomorrow too, probably depending on me, I will shine brighter than today.
よーいどんで僕は変わる 合図は君に出してほしい
I will change on the count of three; I want you to give me the cue.
大冒険する準備ならちゃんと君の分までしといたよ
If it's about preparing for a grand adventure, I've got your share ready too.
どんな時も前を向いて歌っていたい ほらへこんで泣いて辛い時も
I want to keep facing forward and singing no matter what, even when I'm hurting.
強がってるけど平気だよ きっときみのためのならできること
I'm acting tough, but I'm fine; surely for your sake, I can do it.
涙を“大嫌い”にばらまいて 弱くたって虹は呼び出せるよ
Scattering my tears away as something I "hate," I can summon a rainbow.
また明日もたぶん僕次第で 今日よりも輝いていく
Tomorrow too, probably depending on me, I will shine brighter than today.
どんな時も前を向いて歌っていたい ほらへこんで泣いて辛い時も
I want to keep facing forward and singing no matter what, even when I'm hurting.
強がってるけど平気だよ きっときみのためのならできること
I'm acting tough, but I'm fine; surely for your sake, I can do it.
涙を“大嫌い”にばらまいて 弱くたって虹は呼び出せるよ
Scattering my tears away as something I "hate," I can summon a rainbow.
また明日もたぶん僕次第で 今日よりも輝いていく
Tomorrow too, probably depending on me, I will shine brighter than today.
lalala...
やあ！お着替えしてきたよ。
Hey! I went and changed my outfit.
レインボー、どうだったかな？
How was "RAINBOW"?
ダンス、ダンス、ダンス！新しいダンスだったんだけど、どうだったかな？
Dance, dance, dance! It was a new dance, but how was it?
よかった？よかった？リースう、がんばったでしょー？
Was it good? I worked really hard on it, you know?
お？あれ、なんか……あれ、なんか誰か、あぴぴ？誰かきそうな、なんか……
Oh? Wait, I smell something... Is someone coming?
予感がする、あぴぴ？あれ？なんか、わっとめのにおいがする。
I have a feeling... Apipi? Wait, I smell Watame.
その声は……！
That voice is...!
言い出したね。
You made me say it.
ぼたんちゃん！
Botan-chan!
わためさーん。
Watame-san.
なんしょうか？2周年おめでとうございます。
What is it? Happy 2nd anniversary.
ありがとう！おめでとう言いに来てくれたのか。
Thank you! Did you come here to say congratulations?
と、思いましたか？
Or so you thought?
思いましたよ。
I thought so.
あら、おめでとうを……うん、言いに来たと思いましたか？おめでとうを言いに来たと思いました。
Oh, you thought I came to say congratulations?
あ、本当ですか？違うんですか？
Ah, is that true? Is it different?
うーん、ちょっとね、わためめのにおいがしたから、あ、なんかやってんのかなと思って。あ、じゃあ、なんかやってるんだったら、ちょっと乗っ取っちゃおっかなー。
Well, I smelled Watame, so I thought, "Ah, is she doing something?" If so, maybe I'll hijack it.
乗っ取る！？
Hijack!?
え、乗っ取る！？あ、なんか、画面の前のみなさん、どうも獅白ぼたんです。ごらん、ごらん、ごらん……
Eh, hijack!? Everyone in front of the screen, hello, it's Shishiro Botan. Look, look...
なぜね、なんか今日はね、ごらん、ごらん、ごらん、わためめの番組に……
Why, today, look, look, look, on Watame's program...
なんなんだよ
What is this?
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, I see.
ダメダメダメダメ
No, no, no, no!
おめでとうおめでとう
Congratulations, congratulations!
え？乗っ取りに来たの？
Eh? Did you come to hijack it?
また今度やればいいじゃん。
We can just do it next time.
また今度じゃダメじゃん。え？
Next time won't work! Eh?
おかしいおかしいおかしい！
That's weird, that's weird, that's weird!
え？ダメなの？
Eh? Why not?
え？
Eh?
じゃあ、じゃあ…
Then, then...
100歩、いや1万歩譲って
I'll concede 100, no, 10,000 steps—
譲ってくれるの？譲って、譲って。
You'll concede? Please, please!
なんか勝負で、お、勝てたらいいよ。
If I win in a match, is that okay?
皆さん、
Everyone,
うん。
yeah.
現地取りましたよ、今。
We just staked our claim here.
わために勝ったら、じゃあこれ、ししろんバター
If you beat Watame, then this—Shishiro Butter,
おめでとう配信になるってことですね？
will become a celebration stream, right?
なん、何のかな。分かんないけど。
I wonder what it'll be. I have no idea, but—
じゃあちょっと勝負させてくださいよ。
Then please let us have a match.
お、任せるりん。
Oh, I'll leave it to you.
本当に？いいのかな？
Really? Is that okay?
じゃあ、勝負解除とか、あ、準備して、
Then, like, disabling the match... Ah, prepare...
わため道場？
Watame Dojo?
うん、わため道場じゃん。
Yeah, Watame Dojo!
あの、看板を奪ったわため道場かい？
You mean the Watame Dojo that stole the signboard?
その巻き道場があるから、ご機嫌のみんなでじゃんけんしに行って、全員勝って、ね、ことごとくじゃんけん…頭が…猫も杓子もじゃんけん…う、頭が…
There's a Sonomaki Dojo, so everyone go play rock-paper-scissors in high spirits, win against everyone... ugh, my head... rock-paper-scissors everywhere... ugh, my head...
まあちょっと看板を取りに行っちゃおうかな。
Well, I guess we'll go take back the signboard.
勝負といえばあそこだから。
Speaking of matches, that's the place.
そうだな。じゃあ一緒に行こうか。
That's right. Then let's go together.
いいよ。
Sure.
行くよ。
Let's go.
いいよ。
Okay.
ジャンプできる？
Can you jump?
じゃあジャンプしようか。
Then let's jump.
うん。
Yeah.
せーので行くよ。
Let's go on three.
オッケー。
Okay.
せーの！
Ready, set!
ジャンプ！
Jump!
今日はこれで勝負したいと思います！
Today, we'd like to settle this with this!
これだあああ！
This is it!
なにーこれ？
What is this?
1-2-Switchだよ！
It's 1-2-Switch!
えー、ゲーム？ゲームだね。
Eh, a game? It's a game, huh.
そうだよ、ゲームだよ。
That's right, it's a game.
じゃあこれでなんか勝負して、え、何？勝ったらなんかあんの？
Then we'll have a match with this, and... what? Is there something if I win?
勝ったらじゃあ、負けた方の言うことを聞きます！
If I win, then... the loser has to do whatever the winner says!
いいの？そんなこと言っちゃって。
Is that okay? Saying things like that.
記念配信が獅白ぼたんの記念配信になる可能性が…
There's a chance the anniversary stream becomes Shishiro Botan's anniversary stream...
あるけど、いいってことね？
But you're okay with that?
乗っ取りられるの？
It'll get hijacked?
いいね。
Sounds good.
大丈夫、勝つから。よーし頑張ろう！勝とう！
Don't worry, I'll win. Alright, let's do our best! Let's win!
じゃあ一緒に、バトルだあああ！！！
Then together, it's a battleeee!!!
第一試合
Match 1
禅やろっか？
Shall we do Zen?
え？禅やろっか？
Eh? Shall we do Zen?
なにこれ？禅ってなに？なにすんの？
What is this? What is "Zen"? What do we do?
わかんない。
I don't know.
精神の強さどっちが強いか、羊が勝つ！
Which mental strength is stronger, the sheep wins!
片足で立って！
Stand on one leg!
おお！
Oh!
片足だよ！
On one leg!
これつらそう。
This looks tough.
片足で立ってよ！
Stand on one leg!
うわ、これつらーい！
Wow, this is tough!
3、2、1、はじめ！
3, 2, 1, start!
はじめ！
Start!
うー！
Ugh!
あ、まだいけんじゃない？
Ah, we can still go, right?
ここまで！あ、ダメだった！
That's it! Ah, we failed!
ししろの勝ちじゃん！
Shishiro wins!
煙いよ！
It's smoky!
熱い！熱い！熱い！焼かれちゃうよ！ちょっと焦げる焦げる！いぶされちゃう！
Hot! Hot! Hot! I'm gonna get roasted! I'm burning! I'm getting smoked out!
最後のほうでもいい匂いしてたよ、わため。いぶされて。煙たくない？
Watame, you smelled nice toward the end. Getting smoked. Isn't it smokey?
大丈夫大丈夫。ちょっといい感じにローストされてたんだじゃない？
It's fine, it's fine. Weren't you being roasted nicely?
え？燻製？
Eh? Smoked?
え、ちょっといぶされた感想あとで聞かせてよ。
Eh, let me hear your thoughts on being smoked later.
第二試合
Match 2
これは…
This is...
ボクシング！
Boxing!
じゃあやるか。
Then let's do it.
Ready!
相手の目を見ろ！それでお互いに向き合って…相手よりも早く打て！はい！
Look into each other's eyes! Face each other... and hit faster than your opponent! Ready, go!
ストレート！それだ！
Straight! That's it!
連続パンチだ！
Continuous punches!
アッパー！
Uppercut!
アッパーつええ！
Uppercuts are strong!
オラあああ！うっしゃあ！
Oraaaa! Yes!
良いのチャンピオン！
Good champion!
良い脇パィです！
Nice underarm!
あ、でも惜しい！惜しい！
Ah, but close! So close!
1点差か。
1 point difference, huh.
まあね、普段は肉相手に殴ってたからな。
Well, you know, I usually punch meat.
こわっ。
Scary.
第三試合
Match 3
読めるか？
Can you read it?
真剣白刃取り。あーー！
Shinken Shirahadori. Ahhhh!
すごい！
Amazing!
やったことある？
Have you ever done it?
ないよ！
No!
逆に聞きたい、あんのか？
I want to ask you the opposite, have you?
見たこともない。
I've never even seen it.
はじめ！
Start!
美味しいのかな？
I wonder if it's tasty?
なぁ！くっそー！
Take that! Damn it!
くっそー！交互交代！
Damn it! Take turns!
構えて！はじめ！
Get ready! Start!
さあ、じゃあどうしようかな。
Now, what should I do?
いつでもいいの？かかってこい！
Anytime is fine? Bring it on!
そうか。何のタレが好き？
I see. What sauce do you like?
何のタレ？
What sauce?
あと5秒！
5 seconds left!
ちなみに 何のタレが好きなんだい？
By the way, what kind of sauce do you like?
やっぱ焼肉のタレかな
Probably yakiniku sauce, I guess.
ランウェイ歩きたくないかい？
Don't you want to walk the runway?
ぼたんめがじゃあランウェイ歩くの？
So Botan-me, are you walking the runway?
一緒に歩くよ
I'll walk with you.
え、すごい！
Eh, amazing!
あれ…スタイルいいな？
Wait... your figure's great, huh?
やる前からちょっと…
Even before doing it, sort of...
なー！やるー！やる！
Nooo! Let's do it! Let's do it!
チェックするわよ
I'll check it.
どうかな？
How is it?
どう？わかんない
How? I don't know.
やっぱりプロポーションの違いで…
As expected, due to the difference in proportions...
くさーーっ！くさーーっ！
So stinky! So stinky!
エアギターと見えました が
It looked like air guitar, but
初心者だけどやってもいいかな？
I'm a beginner, but is it okay to do it?
まあね、今日はほら、サングラスつけてきたよ
Well, you see, today, look, I wore sunglasses.
かっこいいだろ！
Pretty cool, right!
このサングラスがあればなんかうまく弾ける気がする
With these sunglasses, I feel like I can play well.
確かに
True.
お、やるかじゃあ！できそうな気がしてきた！
Oh, shall we do it then? I feel like I can do it!
やるざ！行こうぜ！
Let's do it! Let's go!
弾いてるぜー！
I'm strumming!
弾けよ！弾いてるぜー！
Rock out! I'm strumming!
あれ…あれあれあれ
Huh... Huh, huh, huh?
音楽を聞かないとだめだな？
You have to listen to the music, huh?
こんんなんやってたからだよ！
That's because you were doing stuff like this!
弾いてねーもん！
I wasn't playing!
あ、そっか
Ah, right.
え、ダメなのか？
Eh, is that no good?
いや、でもちゃんとこうやんないと
Well, but if you don't do it right like this
観客の盛り上がりはね、お互い良かったと思うよ
the audience's hype, I think it was good for both of us.
そうか？
Is that so?
うん、まあ、勝ちだけだな
Yeah, well, just the win though.
くさーーっ！こんなことしたから！こんなこと！止めときゃよかった！
So stinky! Because I did that! Such things! I should've stopped!
勝てないんだけど…勝てないんだけど…
I just can't win... I can't win...
いや全然勝てなくないっすかぁ？
Hey, isn't it true that I can't win at all?
なんすかぁ？全然勝てなくないっすかぁ？
What is it? Isn't it true that I can't win at all?
ちょっと最後5億P入るのやります？
Shall we do one where you get 500 million points at the end?
え、いいの？
Eh, really?
しょうがないなあ
Can't be helped.
いいの？いいよ
Really? Alright.
じゃあ最後に、最後勝った方があれしよう、言うことを聞こう
Then lastly, whoever wins last, let's do that, obey their orders.
まあまあ、反射神経はね、ライオンから逃げてるからね
Well, reflexes, you know, because I'm running away from a lion.
あ、確かに！足は速いもん な
Ah, true! My legs are fast, after all.
勝っちゃうな
I might win.
本当に？
Really?
あー勝っちゃう勝っちゃう！このままだと私5億何ポイントもらうことになると思うけど
Ah, I'll win, I'll win! At this rate, I'll probably get 500 million points or something.
えっ？
Eh?
そんなね、なるわけないよなあ
No way that's gonna happen.
お前の勝ちだ
Your win.
あれあれあれ？
Huh, huh, huh?
5億ね、おめでとう！
500 million, congrats!
ありがとう！じゃあわための…
Thanks! Then Watame's...
なんか次勝った方6億にしよう
How about making the next winner 600 million?
6億！？
600 million!?
6億ポイントにしよう
Let's make it 600 million points.
まあまあまあ、5億より多いしな
Well, well, it's more than 500 million.
そうそうそう。で、言うことを聞こう
That's right. And obey what they say.
なるほど。もっともらえるならいっか！
I see. If I can get more, I guess it's fine!
そうだよ。わためこれ勝ったら11億ポイントだからね
That's right. If Watame wins this, it'll be 1.1 billion points.
すげー！すげーよ！たんまりたんまり♪
Amazing! Amazing! Plenty, plenty♪
どうだ
How's that?
お前の勝ちだ
It's your win.
folkで惑わしてきた！
I confused you with folk!
ツンツンしてやったぜ
I poked you right back!
え、ていうこと、6億Pはわため？
Wait, what? 600 million points for Watame?
違うよ！わためは5億Pで獅白が6億Pだから、獅白の勝ち！
No! Watame got 500 million and Shishiro got 600 million, so Shishiro wins!
勝者！獅白ぼたん！
Winner: Shishiro Botan!
えええええええ！
Ehhhhhh?!
いっぱい負けたからね
Because you lost a lot, you know.
しょうがない…
Can't be helped...
いいよ、またじゃあ今度遊ぼうぜ
Alright, let's play again sometime.
遊ぼうよ、また！じゃあ言うこと聞いてもらおうかな
Let's play again! Then I'll have you listen to what I say!
せっかくだし、ちょっと私のさ、オリ曲をさ、一緒に歌うとかどうです？
Since we're at it, how about you sing my original song together with me?
歌いたいと思ってた！えっ、いいの？
I've been wanting to sing it! Eh, really?
いいよ、それだったらわためもね、負けても楽しいし私も嬉しいし
Sure, if that's the case, even if Watame loses, it's fun and I'm happy too.
優しい！
How kind!
いいじゃないですかね
Isn't that nice?
いいね！歌わせていただきます！
Awesome! I'll gladly sing it!
では一緒に歌ってください！お願いします！
Please sing along with us! Please!
白銀の獅子は走って走って走り続けている
The silver lioness dashes, dashes, and continues dashing
もう不安に振り返ることはないから
Because she doesn't look back with fear anymore
百獣の王は九十九を信じるから王なんだ
The king of a hundred beasts is a king because she believes in the 99
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride
それこそ私の誇り
That is the reason for my pride
孤高は孤独の裏返しで
Solitude is the opposite of loneliness
ずっと一匹なんだろうって思っていた
I wondered if I would always be alone
前だけ睨んでた 夢へ向かって
Simply looking forward with a glare, towards my dreams
足跡を見失って
I've lost track of my footsteps
変わらない曇天 交わらない動点
An unchanging cloudy sky, a point that cannot cross
「はぐれ山猫だ」って笑った
"I'm a wildcat who's lost her pack," I laughed
音のなかった世界 満ちて広げていく
A world without sound was quickly filling and expanding
人たちの声や 野生の目に晒されて
The voices of humankind, held up to the wild eye
私は変わりつつある 蕾の lioness
I'm slowly changing, a budding lioness
立ってなお爪を研ぐ 友の前 歩くため
Standing and sharpening her claws so she can walk forward with her friends
真っ白い獅子は群れて群れて群れを抱く
The white lioness cherishes those who flock, flock to her
それが私を支えてくれるから
Because they are willing to support me
純白の孤高を追って寄り添ってくれるモノたち
Those who pursued and nestled close to the pure white one of solitude
we have the pride, and it's our reason of pride
それこそ私の誇り
That is the reason for my pride
だけど
But
解きほぐして縄張りの
Untangling the boundaries of our territory
線を 上手くでむさべつに引いてた
Skillfully and indiscriminately drawing lines
目指したものだけ 遥か雲のものだけ 探して迷うだけ
Just searching and getting lost for what I aimed for, for things far in the clouds
見失った絹の ふわふわまどまま
The lost silk, soft and hazy
導いて走って 気づいた ある日
Guiding and running, I realized one day
独りじゃなかったことに やがて気づくよ
That I wasn't alone, I eventually realized
私たちの熱 少しずつとも
Our warmth, little by little...
燃えていくから
Is burning up
もし遠く ずっと遠く 離れていても
Even if we are far, far apart
びびずに負け吠える
Roaring without fear even in defeat
共に声届けるため
To deliver our voices together
一人の獅子は 最低最低 先吠えたいのさ
The single lioness wants to roar first, at her lowest
燃える時は 見守る人のために
When she burns, it's for those who watch over her
夜間の王は 一緒に一緒に先吠えたいのさ
The night king wants to roar first together
We can be the king of beasts together
白銀の獅子は
The silver lioness
駆け抜けて 駆け抜けて 駆け抜けて行く もうすぐ
is running through, running through right now.
見失うことはないから
Because she will never lose sight.
百獣の王は究極を信じるからおがのさ
The king of beasts believes in the ultimate.
まだまだ今日 吹雪の中を 見て走っていられる
Still today, running through the blizzard,
後ろの 2人接吻は
the footsteps behind us
私たちの 道を守るから
will protect our path, so
We have the pride in the horizon pride. 雑踏さえ私達の誇り！
Even the hustle and bustle is our pride!
ぼたんちゃん顔見えてへんで！
Botan-chan, your face isn't showing!
あー！
Ah!
顔見えてへんで！
Your face wasn't showing!
でもね、わためとね、ライオネスプライドをまさか一緒に歌えるとはね、ねえ！
I never thought I'd get to sing "Lioness' Pride"
思わなかったよ。 ねぇ！
together with Watame! Really!
いや歌いたかったから嬉しいよ。
Well, I wanted to sing it so I'm so happy.
ありがとうな。ちょっとこの歌好きなんだよね、っていうのは噂に聞いてましたよ。
Thanks. I heard rumors you really liked this song.
いや、でもね、挑戦したことがあるんだよな。
Well, you know, I actually tried challenging it before.
そうなの？
Is that so?
うん、一緒に歌いたかったんだよ！
Yeah, I wanted to sing it together!
ありがとうな！
Thank you!
ありがとう！ 歌えた！
Thank you, we sang it!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え、でもさ、これ1曲だけ？
Eh, but is this just one song?
え？1曲で終わっちゃうの？
Eh? Is it ending with just one song?
まだ歌いたいな、一緒に。
I want to sing more together.
一緒に歌いたいよね！
We want to sing together!
歌いたいな！
I want to sing!
え、でもなんか曲あったっけ？
Eh, but are there any other songs?
なんかあるんじゃないんですか？
Isn't there something?
え？
Eh?
なんかあるんじゃないんですか？知ってんじゃないんですか？
Isn't there? Don't you know?
いやー、なんか噂によると、今日わためぇの配信で
Well, rumor has it that today, on Watame's stream,
初めて聴ける歌があるとかないとか？
there's a song we can hear for the very first time.
おっ、あるとかないとか？
Oh, is there or isn't there?
あるんです！
There is!
え！？
Eh?!
えーーー！
Whaaa?!
聴きたいな！
I want to hear it!
ねぇ！ みんな知らないのかな？
Right? Do you all not know?
おっ、知らない？もしやみんな、知らないらしいよ。
Oh, you don't know? Apparently, everyone doesn't know.
知らないらしいぜ？
They don't know?
どうする、どうする？
What should we do?
教えてあげるか？
Shall we tell them?
そうだな、しょー、しょーがねえな、教えてやるか！しょーがねえな！
That's right, we have no choice, we'll tell you!
教えてあげよう、ほら！
Let's teach you, look!
なあ！
Right?!
曲名歌ってくださいよ！
Please sing the song title!
あ、いいよ、ちょっとわためぇの配信だし、わためから聴きたいな。
Ah, sure, since it's Watame's stream, I want to hear it from Watame.
さっき負けたけどええか？ いいよ！
Is it okay even though I lost earlier? Sure!
ほんならよ、で、どうぞ！
Well then, go ahead!
なんと、獅子わたオリジナル曲！
It's none other than the ShishiWata original song!
獅子わたクッキングが！ イェーイ！イェーイ！ 完成しまして！
"ShishiWata Cooking"! Yay! It's complete!
そう、ね！
That's right, yeah!
今日はぜひね、今この配信を見ている皆さんにね、はい。お聞かせしたいなと思ってね。はい。
Today, we definitely wanted to let everyone watching this stream listen to it.
一ち早くね、お届けしたいなと思いまして。
We wanted to deliver it to you as soon as possible.
そうね。
That's right.
え、じゃあさいて、うん。
Eh, then...
どうする？
What should we do?
ここで歌うの？ この、あ、ここじゃない方がいいよね。
Do we sing here? This... Ah, it's better not here, right?
あ、そう？
Oh, really?
うん、クッキングだからね。
Yeah, because it's cooking.
あ、そうだよね。獅子わたクッキングだから、なんかちょっとちゃんと調理できそうな。ね？
Since it's ShishiWata Cooking, we should be able to properly cook.
そうよね。ちゃんとね、装備も整えて。
That's right. Properly getting our equipment ready.
いる装備？
Is equipment needed?
うん、いるいるいる！
Yeah, it is, it is!
じゃナイフ持っていくね。
Then I'll bring a knife.
ナイフ？ あ、ちょっと、お、お。
A knife? Ah, wait, oh, oh.
危ないね。
That's dangerous.
危ない危ない、あの、なんか、お、危ないよ。
Dangerous, dangerous, um, like, oh, it's dangerous.
なんかフォークっぽいのも持ってくわ。
I'll bring something like a fork too.
うん、それも危険だけどね（笑）
Yeah, that's dangerous too, haha.
まあ、移動しますか。
Well, shall we move?
そうね、移動しましょうじゃあ！うん、はい。
That's right, let's move then! Yeah, okay.
ではは。
Now then.
はい。
Yes.
いーーだーーー！
Movingーーー!
皆様ごきげんよう。
Greetings, everyone.
後ろ風料理学校講師のエリザベス獅子郎で。
I am Elizabeth Shishiro, instructor at Ushirofu Cooking School.
ししのメリーわためです。
And I'm Shishi's Merry Watame.
早速お料理のお勉強始めていきましょうか、わためさん。はい、先生！
Let's start learning how to cook right away, Watame-san. Yes, teacher!
大すき！ししわたクッキング
I love it! ShishiWata Cooking
まずは卵ぽいと入れて、トントントントン腕を振るいましょう
First, toss in an egg, tap-tap-tap-tap, let's swing our arms!
あっちっち！だけどにごりようじに楽しくお料理を
It's hot! But let's happily cook together!
先生、次は何をすればいいですか？
Sensei, what should we make next?
料理とaimですね、コツがいるんですよ
Cooking and aim, you see. There's a trick to it.
なるほど！
I see!
大好き！ししわたクッキング
We love it! ShishiWata Cooking!
まずはたまごpoiッと入れて
First, toss the egg in, poi!
トントンツン腕を振りましょう
Tap, tap, tap, swing your arm!
あちちち！（あちちー！）
Hot, hot, hot! (So hot!)
火傷にご用心
Watch out for burns.
楽しくお料理♪
Cooking is so fun♪
混ぜよ 使うのは“つのドリル”
Mix it, using the "Horn Drill"!
「うりゃりゃりゃ～！」
"Uryaryarya~!"
特製ソース作りましょう
Let's make a special sauce.
飛ぶぞ！（どーん！）つければわかる
You'll fly! (Boom!) You'll know if you try.
素敵なお料理♪
Such a wonderful dish♪
さあさあ今日のメインの料理
Now, today's main dish:
コンソメ風味のジンギスカン
Consommé-flavored Genghis Khan!
な、なんか言って おります けれど (^ ^；
Or so she says... (^ ^;
「…冗談、だよ ねぇ？」
"...Just kidding, right?"
隠し味だから「ふふ、冗談ですの」
"Hehe, just kidding," as a secret ingredient.
スタンバイ さあ どうぞ
Stand by, now go ahead.
テーブルへ ご案内
Right this way to the table.
とっておきの愛情込めて 美味しくなれ（美味しくなれ）
Pouring all our love into it, make it delicious!
エプロンつけて お料理するよ
Put on our aprons and start cooking!
おいいで おいいで こっちこっち（はい！はい！あっーーうっ！）
Come here, this way (Yes! Yes! Ahーーugh!)
一緒に食べればハッピー 溢れるね（溢れるね）
Eating together fills us with happiness!
そんな時間が こんな笑顔が
Times like these, smiles like these,
大好き！ししわたクッキング
We love it! ShishiWata Cooking!
「説明しよう！しししろフーズ調理学校とは！」
Let us explain! What is Shishiro Foods Cooking Academy?
えっ とですね、美味しいラム肉料理を研究する…
Um, well, researching delicious lamb dishes...
…ねぇぼたんちゃん、これカンペ合ってる？
"...Hey Botan-chan, is this cue card right?"
合ってますよー
"That's right~"
ふ、ふーん
"I-I see."
あ、食材がない
"Ah, we're out of ingredients."
そうして新たな食材を探しにサバンナの奥地へとやってきたのであった
And so, they set off deep into the savanna...
探せ 豪華三大和牛「ぱおん」
Search for the luxury trio of Wagyu, "Paon"!
情け容赦 サバイバル
No mercy in this survival!
ドッドッ！（どーん！）肉体言語
Thump thump! (Boom!) The language of the flesh.
ガンガンキマっ てく
Going hard and strong.
仕留めはバッチリと 任せてくださいよ
Leave the takedown completely to me.
なんとかしてくれる ししろぼたん
Shishiro Botan will somehow make it work.
この世はまるっと「さんかくしかく！」
This world is all "triangle and square!"
弱肉強食「じゅるり…」「ひえっ…！」
Survival of the fittest: "Drool..." "Eep...!"
もうダメ 腹ペコ
We can't take it, we're starving!
さあさ 早く食べよう
Come on, let's eat quickly!
太陽の下 ピクニック とか
A picnic under the sun,
楽しいよね（楽しいよね）
Is so much fun!
色とりどりの おべんと箱 へ詰めて詰めよ トキメキ（はい！はい！あっーーうっ！）
Packing colorful bento boxes with excitement!
目と目合わせ てハッピー 召し上がれ（召し上がれ）
Eye-to-eye happiness, bon appétit!
そんな時間が こんな笑顔が
Times like these, smiles like these,
大好き！ししわたクッキング
We love it! ShishiWata Cooking!
hey yo 腹減らpeople put your hands up 紹介する 今宵 の出演者「オニーク！」
Hey yo, hungry people put your hands up! Presenting tonight's cast: "Oniku!"
待てないライオンガール 奴とは ちょっと 因縁がある
An impatient lion girl. We've got a bit of history.
「どや！」ライムを刻んで ライムを紡ぐ
"Doya!" Rhymes carved, rhymes spun.
スタイルがマイクブーム 悪く はないよ 鉄板ネタ
Style is mic boom, solid material.
産地直送 エンターテイナー いつか遠い未来で思い出す
Direct from the farm, entertainers. Remembering in some distant future.
そんな時間を こんな笑顔を
Times like these, smiles like these,
もっともっと作ろうよ
Let's make even more!
とっておきの愛情込めて 美味しくなれ（美味しくなれ）
Pouring all our love into it, make it delicious!
みんなの為に お 料理する よ
Cooking for everyone's sake!
おいいで おいいで こっちこっち（はい！はい！あっーーうっ！）
Come here, this way (Yes! Yes! Ahーーugh!)
一緒に食べればハッピー 溢れるね（溢れるね）
Eating together fills us with happiness!
そんな時間と こんな笑顔を
Times like these, smiles like these,
毎日 お届けする
Delivering every single day.
人気番組！ししわたクッキング「グぅ！」
Popular show! ShishiWata Cooking: "Goo!"
「それではみなさん、また明日～！」
"Well then everyone, see you tomorrow~!"
「明日の素材は、新鮮なラム肉です～」
"Tomorrow's ingredient is fresh lamb meat~"
「…なんて？」
"...What was that?"
いつか遠い未来で 思い出す
Remembering in some distant future,
そんな時間を こんな笑顔を
Times like these, smiles like these,
もっともっと作ろうよ
Let's make even more!
とっておきの愛情込めて 美味しくなれ（美味しくなれ）
Pouring all our love into it, make it delicious!
みんなの為に お料理するよ
Cooking for everyone's sake!
おいいで おいいで こっちこっち（はい！はい！あっーーうっ！）
Come here, this way (Yes! Yes! Ahーーugh!)
一緒に食べればハッピー 溢れるね（溢れるね）
Eating together fills us with happiness!
そんな時間と こんな笑顔を
Times like these, smiles like these,
毎日お届けする
Delivering every single day.
人気番組！ししわたクッキング
Popular show! ShishiWata Cooking!
ししわたクッキング
ShishiWata Cooking!
毎日お届けする 人気番組！ ししわたクッキング「グぅ！」
Delivering daily, ShishiWata Cooking, Goo!
「それではみなさん、また明日～！」
"Well then everyone, see you tomorrow~!"
「明日の素材は、新鮮なラム肉です～」
"Tomorrow's ingredient is fresh lamb meat~"
「…なんて？」
"...What was that?"
「楽しかったね！」「楽しかったね！」
"That was so fun!" "So fun!"
ということでわためぇ、この曲は一体何なんだい？
So Watame, what on earth is this song?
この曲はししわたのオリジナルソングでぇす！いえーい！
This song is ShishiWata's original song! Yay!
今日初公開だよね？「ね、そうなんですよ」
It's our first time showing it today, right? "Yeah, that's right."
ってことは、なんかこの後動画とか出たりするの？
Does that mean a video will come out after this?
お、なんかあれ後ろに、おっおっおっ？これさ、帽子でかーい！
Oh, wait, behind us... Oh? This is... The hat is huge!
このね 小戸都先生にね イラストを描いていただきまして この後
Thanks to Kazato-sensei, who drew an illustration for us,
10時 15分に わためのチャンネルで 投稿をいたします！
at 10:15, I will be posting it on my channel!
イエーイ！ イエーイ！
Yay! Yay!
ぼたんちゃんありがとう。
Thanks, Botan.
楽しみ！ 楽しみ！
I'm so excited!
ぜひね ちょっとね 動画でまたね みんなに見ていただけたら 嬉しいなと ね！思いますけれども。 見てください。
I'd be so happy if everyone could check it out in the video again, right? Please take a look.
はい。え… これだけ？
Yeah. Wait... is that it?
まさかまさか！ まさかこれだけじゃありません！ ありません！
No way, no way! That's definitely not all of it! Not at all!
じゃあちょっとあたためさん。 はい。 教えてくださいよ。
Then Watame-san, please tell us.
実は、角巻わため 2周年グッズが、 発売になりまして、おっ！
Actually, Tsunomaki Watame's 2nd-anniversary merch is going on sale!
その中のグッズ、 わためのうたボリューム2 アルバムに、なります！
And among those goods is 'Watame no Uta Vol. 2' album!
イエーイ！ スペシャルトラックでね、このシシワタ・クッキングも入ってますのでね。
Yay! It also includes 'ShishiWata Cooking' as a special track!
え、いいのにを入れてもらって。 え、こっちコースもいいのを入れちゃって。
Oh, thanks for putting in a good one. Putting in a good track for my side, too.
ありがとう、嬉しい。
Thank you, I'm so happy.
全11曲だよ、 スペシャルトラックに、ね。
All 11 tracks, including the special track, you know.
ありがとう入れてくれてありがとうな。 ちょっと
Thanks for putting it in, thanks a lot.
え、ちなみに、じゃあわための歌だけ？
Wait, by the way, are they all Watame's songs?
え？どういうこと？ え、その、出、出るっていうのは。
Huh? What do you mean? What do you mean by them 'coming out'?
あ、なるほど！いや、わための歌ボリューム2だけじゃないんです、実は！
Ah, I see! No, it's not just Watame no Uta Vol. 2, actually!
え、いいんですか、聞かせてよ、聞かせて。
Oh really? Let us hear it, let us hear!
わための歌ボリューム2 制作秘話ブックレットが出まーす！
The 'Watame no Uta Vol. 2 Production Secret Story Booklet' is coming out!
イエーイ！わあ可愛い。
Yay! Aww, it's cute.
なんとね、ま、このアルバムを作るまでに ソロライブとか色々ありましてね。
And you know, leading up to making this album, there were solo lives and all sorts of things.
この曲に対するちょっとね、え、わための気持ち、お気持ち？ お気持ち詰まってる？
My feelings towards these songs... my feelings? Are my feelings packed in here?
じゃあちょっと見たいな、 わためのお気持ち。
Well, I'd love to see Watame's feelings.
お気持ち恥ずかしいな、 そう言われるとちょっと見られるのは恥ずかしいけど。
Feelings? That's embarrassing, hearing you say that makes it embarrassing to be seen.
いや、どんな気持ちでね、 その曲歌ったとかさ、色々見れるってことね。
I mean, being able to see what kind of feelings you had when singing those songs and stuff.
そうだよ、色々ね書きつまっとる。 ちなみにこれふみ先生の描き下ろしじゃん。 あのCD、CDも見れる？
That's right, a lot of stuff is packed in there. By the way, this is drawn by Fumi-sensei. Can we see the CD too?
これはね、ラフ段階のねイラストなんだけど、 それを表紙にさせていただきまして、 こちらが
This is an illustration from the rough draft stage, which we used for the cover, and this is...
CDのジャケットのイラストになります！
the CD jacket illustration!
かわいいね、 空飛んでるね。
How cute, flying in the sky.
ねえ、羊もよう空飛んどるね。 空飛ぶ時代になったんじゃ。
Yeah, the sheep is flying in the sky. It's truly an age of flying.
ええ、すごいな。進化してるな。 そうだよ。まだまだ、お、まだある？ まだまだグッズも進化しますよ。
Woah, amazing. It's evolving. That's right. There's more—oh, more? The merch is evolving even further.
お、聞かせて聞かせて。 なんと、LEDアクリルスタンドライトも出まーす！
Oh, let me hear, let me hear. And the LED acrylic stand light is coming out!
LED？ あ、可愛い！
LED? Aw, cute!
可愛いよね。何々これ？ 日本一ソフトウェアさん知ってる？
So cute. What's this? Do you know Nippon Ichi Software?
あ、知ってる知ってる。 流行り神とかやってたよ。 ああ、やってたね、そういえば。 やってたやってた。
Oh, I know, I know. They made Hayarigami and stuff. Ah, that's right, they did. They definitely did.
ま、その日本一さんの作品の中でも、 「嘘つき姫と盲目王子」とか、そういったゲームのイラストを 書いていらっしゃる、小田沙耶佳先生に 描き下ろしていただいたんですよ！
Among Nippon Ichi's works, Oda Sayaka-sensei, who draws illustrations for games like 'The Liar Princess and the Blind Prince', drew this exclusively for us!
ええ、めっっちゃかわいい、 本和化してる。
Woah, super cute, so heartwarming.
なんとこれ下からね ライトがポワァーと当たってね えー！
And the light glows softly from underneath— Whoa!
弱火？ 弱火？
Low heat? Low heat?
LED弱火のこと？ LED弱火のこと？
Does LED mean low heat?
火は灯さんだけど。 火は灯さんだけどね。
Well, it doesn't light a fire. It doesn't actually burn.
なるほどね。じゃあ幻想的なわためが 見れってことね。 そうだね。
I see. So we get to see a fantastical Watame. That's right.
へえ、すごいね。あったけね、 わためが見れますよ。癒やされてってください。
Woah, amazing. Warm and cozy Watame can be seen. Please be healed by it.
いや、まだ終わらない。 え、まだあるの？ まだあります。なんと！
No, it's not over yet. Wait, there's more? There's more. And!
シチュエーションボイスも出まーす！
Situation voice packs are coming out too!
どんなやつ？ これは
What kind? This is
あの、ソロライブがね、 あったじゃないですか。
Um, you know how there was a solo live?
その、帰り道ね、 君と2人でみたいな
On the way back from that, like, just the two of us...
見たわための妄想が、妄想が、 ジュルリみたいなやつ？ そうなんだ。妄想が恥ずかしい！
Watame's delusions of seeing it, delusions like... drooling? That's it. Her delusions are embarrassing!
え、これわためが書いたの？ そうだよ。シナリオ？そうだよ。
Wait, did Watame write this? That's right. The scenario? That's right.
え、そうなの？全部考えて。 すごいじゃん！
Really? You thought of everything. That's amazing!
そうだよ。これはぜひちょっと 聞きたいね。
That's right. You definitely gotta hear this.
恥ずかしい！ どんな気持ちで書いたんだい？ お気持ち、妄想がいっぱい詰まっております。 あ、恥ずかしいな、見たいな、お気持ち。
Embarrassing! What kind of feelings did you write this with? Feelings and delusions are packed to the brim. Ah, how embarrassing, yet I wanna see those feelings.
でもこれ セット販売もね、ありまして。
But there's also a set bundle available.
はい、セット販売だと、 あの、箔押しサインにはなっちゃうんですけども、 ポストカードがついたりとか、特典ボイスがついてきたりとかします。
Yes, with the set purchase, um, it comes with a foil-stamped autograph, plus a postcard and bonus voice tracks!
なんと1万エン！ や、買おう！
And it's 10,000 yen! Let's buy it!
イエーイ！ イエーイ！
Yay! Yay!
ちなみにこれは新しいホロライブショップに販売されると
By the way, these will be sold on the new Hololive shop...
そうです！
That's right!
何時から？
Starting at what time?
お、この後なんと10時から！
Oh, starting at 10:00 right after this!
10時からだぞ、みんな。
Starting at 10:00, everyone,
それぞれに単品売りもありますので、よろしくお願いします！
individual items will also be sold, so please check them out!
楽しみだね。
I'm looking forward to it.
うんうんうんうんうん、ええ？
Yeah, yeah, yeah... Eh?
そっか。
I see.
そうなんですけど、じゃあ後で買うね、これ。
That's right, so I'll buy it later, then.
あげるよ、あげるよ！
I'll give it to you!
え、くれるの？あげるよ、あげるよ！ありがとう！
Eh, you'll give it to me? Thank you!
で、この後10時15分からシショーダクッキングの動画が
And after that, at 10:15, the Shishiro Cooking video
そう、上がりますので！10時と10時15分もチェックしてください！
will go up, so please check out both 10:00 and 10:15!
ください！
Please!
さて、そんなこんなで、あの綿芽さん、この後何か注文が入ってるんですか？
Now then, with that said, Watame-san, do you have any orders coming in after this?
いや実わね、マイソングの注文が入ってるんですよね。
Well, actually, orders for "My Song" have come in.
マイソングといえば？
Speaking of "My Song"...?
このアルバムの表題曲になっております。
It's the title track of this album.
なるほど。じゃあこの注文はちょっと綿芽さん1人で頑張って貰いたいなと思うので、エリザベス獅子白は次のね、授業に行ってまいります。
I see. Well, I think you should work hard on this order by yourself, Watame-san, so Elizabeth Shishiro will head to her next class.
先生寂しいけど、うん。
Teacher, I'll miss you, but yeah.
助手のメリーはため頑張りたいと思います！
Assistant Mary Watame will do her best!
頑張ってな。うん。ちゃんとしっかり食材は余らすことなく使うんだぞ。
Do your best. Make sure you use all the ingredients without any leftovers.
食材？
Ingredients?
しっかりね、弱火でじっくりお山た通りにね歌いたいと思います。
Make sure to sing it carefully on low heat, just like the recipe says.
ではマイソング聴いてください！
Now, please listen to "My Song"!
新しく作ったもの以外が奇麗に見えた
Everything other than what I newly made looked pristine.
どうせこんなもんか、ちっぽけだった
I thought, "Is this really it? It was so small."
素笑いばっかが得意になった
I became so good at faking smiles.
けど一番笑えへんのはこのプライドだ
But the hardest thing to laugh at is this pride of mine.
一生懸命なんか全部無駄だったんだ
As if all my hard work was completely meaningless.
ああもう嫌になった
Oh, I'm sick of it already.
「逃げたくない」って聞こえた これは僕の声？
I heard "I don't want to run away." Is this my voice?
1回10回破壊、世界挑戦を続けるよ
Ten times, a hundred times, destroying and repeating, I'll keep challenging the world!
まだ足りないって思ってる
I still feel like it's not enough.
止まない雨の中
Inside the ceaseless rain,
ずっと考えて考えて考えて見つけ出せ僕だけの
keeping thinking, thinking, thinking, and finally finding my very own...
滑走路を証明したいんだよな
runway, I want to prove it, don't I?
そうだろう？
Wouldn't I?
焦り上がる心拍数に嘘つくように
As if lying to the accelerating heart rate,
自分を治つける切符はいらない
I don't need a ticket to comfort myself.
それも今宵仮に置き換えたらさ
If I replace that with tonight temporarily,
今日もまた挑むべきハードルがほら見えただろう
look, the hurdles I should challenge today have appeared, right?
葛藤の隙まで
Right up to the cracks of inner conflict,
錆びない生命をひねり出せるか
can I twist out an unrusting life?
出ないのならとっくに諦めてるよ
If I couldn't, I would have given up long ago.
渾身の信念で歌ったって届くわけじゃない
Singing with all my heart and conviction doesn't mean it'll reach everyone,
素晴らしいかい僕らの現実は残酷だ
how wonderful... our reality is cruel.
曖昧を削り取って尖らせてまた歌ってあきらめる
Shaving off ambiguity, sharpening it, singing again, and the reason to give up...
理由なら過去に捨ててきた
I left behind in the past.
愛してたいよ
I want to love.
立ち止まる度に進みしたがる足を笑いこもうもっといこう
Every time I stop, let's laugh at my feet that want to push forward, let's go further!
小さくて頼りなくて不安定な歩幅が
My small, unreliable, unstable stride
繋がって歌いなるぼくは切ってこれ
connects and turns into song, I cut through this!
1回10回破壊、世界挑戦を続けるよ
Ten times, a hundred times, destroying and repeating, I'll keep challenging the world!
まだ足りないって思ってる
I still feel like it's not enough.
止まない雨の中
Inside the ceaseless rain,
ずっと考えて考えて考えて見つけ出せ僕だけの
keeping thinking, thinking, thinking, and finally finding my very own...
滑走路を証明したいんだよな
runway, I want to prove it, don't I?
もし辿り着いたなら誇っていこうな
If I finally reach it, let's be proud of it!
みんなー！
Everyone!
マイソング聴いてくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for listening to my song!
心を込めて、歌わせていただきました。
I sang it with all my heart.
力みすぎちゃったよ。
I put a bit too much strength into it.
ありがとう！今マイソングのね、動画も絶賛制作中なので、お待ちください。
Thank you! We're currently producing the music video for "My Song," so please look forward to it.
あと、グッズなんですけど、ちょっとね、追加で言いたいこともあるので、もう1回説明してもいいですか？
Also, regarding the goods, there's something extra I wanted to mention. May I explain them one more time?
いい？
Is that okay?
大丈夫？
Are you sure?
じゃあもう1回お願いします！
Then please let me go over it once more!
どどん！角巻わため
Ta-da! Tsunomaki Watame
活動2周年記念、このあと10時発売になります！イェーイ！
2nd Anniversary Goods go on sale at 10:00! Yay!
細かいとこも見ていくと、
And if we look at the finer details...
なんと、角巻わため「わためのうたvol.2」セカンドアルバムが出ます！
We have the 2nd album, Tsunomaki Watame's "Watame no Uta Vol. 2," coming out!
ありがとう！みんなのおかげでセカンドアルバムを出すことができるようになりました。本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thanks to everyone, I'm able to release my 2nd album. Thank you all so much!
セトリがね、ソロライブでも披露させていただいた曲プラス、シシワタクッキングがボーナストラックで入りまして、
The setlist includes songs I performed at my solo live, plus "ShishiWata Cooking" as a bonus track,
この順番とかも自分で考えたんですよ。こっちにしようかなとか、この曲とにしようかなとか考えたので是非聴いてほしいなと思います。
and I thought of the track order myself. I spent time deciding which song should go where, so I really hope you'll listen to it.
で、ジャケットイラストはホーミママが描いてくださっているんですけど、
Also, the jacket illustration was drawn by Homi-mama.
けど、なんとこちらね、アルバムとしても是非買ってもらいたいんだけど、
But you know, while I'd love for you to buy the physical album,
このあと24時からサブスク配信もありますのでね、アルバムとしてお部屋に置いたりとか、
subscription streaming starts at midnight tonight too. Whether you want to display it in your room,
聴く用とか配信用とか保存用とか、あとは配信用とかね、買いたい人はグッズで買って、音源だけでいいかなって方はサブスクの方でも買えますのでね、
listen to it, keep it as a collection item, or stream it—if you want the physical goods, you can buy them, but if you just want the music, you can use the streaming service,
24時から是非チェックしてください。
so please check it out starting at midnight.
そして、あのアルバムとしてね、お手元に置いたりとか、
And you can keep it close at hand as an album,
お、「わためのうたvol.2」
Oh, "Watame no Uta Vol. 2"
制作秘話ブックレットが出ます！なんとA4版16ページ！
Production Secret Story Booklet is coming out! A4 size, 16 pages!
多いね！
That's a lot!
これわためもね、ツラツラと曲に対する思いとか、こういう気持ちで歌ったよとか、こういう風に歌詞を書いたよとか、そういうのを書き連ねたいと思いますので、よかったら手に取って読んでみてほしいなと思います。
I poured my feelings and thoughts about each song into it—how I felt when I sang them, why I wrote certain lyrics—so I really hope you'll pick it up and read through it.
そして、LEDアクリルスタンドライト！
And next, the LED Acrylic Stand Light!
これはいまね、悪い王様と立派な勇者っていう日本一ソフトウェアさんのゲームをやらせてもらってるんですけど、そのキャラクターデザインだったり背景とかイラスト全般を担当されている小田沙耶佳先生にお願いをしまして、
Right now, I'm doing a let's play of Nippon Ichi Software's "The Wicked King and the Noble Hero," and I asked Saayaka Oda-sensei, who handles the character designs, backgrounds, and overall illustrations,
なんとわためのおりょくほりデイズをイメージして書いていただいたんですよ。
to draw an illustration inspired by Watame's "HoliDays."
だから猫とか鳥とか花とか、歌詞に出てくるんだけど、それを表現していただきました。
So cats, birds, flowers, which appear in the lyrics, were all incorporated into the design.
下からね、あたたか、ポワッとした光が漏れてきて、綺麗になりますのでね、
Warm, soft light spills out from underneath, making it look so pretty,
よかったら、おうちに置いてほしいなと思います。
so I hope you'll display it in your room.
そして！
And!
これフルセット全部ですね、購入していただいた方には、箱推しじゃないけど、サイン入りポストカード＋特典ボイスが聴けます！フルセットを購入した人しか聴けない特典ボイスがついてくるので、是非聴いてほしいなと思います。
For those who purchase the complete full set, you'll get a signed postcard plus exclusive voice tracks that only full-set buyers can hear! So I really hope you'll check that out.
あとは、特典じゃないんだけど、さっきも言ったんだけどね、記念ボイス、ソロライブの後キミと二人で見たら自分でね、考えた妄想がね詰まってるボイスもありますのでね、これも是非聴いてほしいなと思います。
Also, as I mentioned earlier, there's an anniversary voice pack where I imagine watching the solo live together with you, filled with my silly delusions, so I hope you'll give that a listen too.
こんなもんかな？
I think that's about it?
はい！ということでこのあと10時からはグッズをチェックしていただいて、10時15分はシシワタクッキングをチェックしていただいて、24時はサブスク配信ありますのでわためのうたvol.2を是非ゲットしてほしいなと思います。
Right! So starting at 10:00, please check out the goods; at 10:15, check out ShishiWata Cooking; and at midnight, subscription streaming begins, so I hope you'll all grab "Watame no Uta Vol. 2"!
ここまで聞いてくれて、で、噛んじゃった
Thank you for listening all the way through—and I stumbled over my words!
見てくれて、見てくれて、本当に、みんな、ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much, everyone, for watching!
今年はね、ソロライブをさせて、いただいたりとか、あの、がっつりにライブというものをさせていただいたので
This year, I was able to have solo live performances and a really solid concert experience.
今日のね、2周年はちょっと、あの、お遊び入れたりとか、あとはゲストを、え、呼ばせていただいて、あの、一緒に歌ってもらったりとかしていただいたんだけど
So today's 2nd anniversary had some fun activities, and we invited guests to sing along with me,
ふう、楽しんでもらえたかな？
Whew, I wonder if you enjoyed it?
いつもドキドキだよ。
My heart is always pounding.
今年は、本当に、いろいろ、え、忙しい、ドタバタした1年だったんだけど
This year was really a busy and frantic year with all sorts of things.
オリ曲ね、10曲プラス、あと、ユニットとかで2曲、プラス、あのシシワタンクッキングの方も、え、やって13曲ね、
Including 10 original songs, plus 2 unit songs, and Shishiwatan Cooking, making 13 songs in total!
新しい曲を覚えて歌ったりとか、え、したんだけど、そういう機会をもらえるのも本当にねみんなのおかげだと思っています。ありがとうございます！
I memorized and sang new songs, and I really feel that getting those opportunities is all thanks to everyone. Thank you so much!
本当に感謝、あの、言っても、あの、言っても言っても言っても言っても足りないくらいなんだけど、本当にありがとうございました！
I can't thank you enough no matter how many times I say it. Thank you so much!
では、
Now then,
また、3年目も、よろしくお願いします！
I look forward to your support in our 3rd year as well!
最後は、あのポーズ、やるぞ！
For the finale, we'll do that pose!
分かる？あのポーズ。わためといったら、あのポーズ。
You know it, right? That pose. If it's Watame, it's that pose.
決めますよ、最後に。
I'll strike it at the end.
では、わため、ナンバーワン！またねー！
Ready... Watame Number One! See you later!